## Tim Caswell

821 Dublin #105 Richardson, TX 75080 Phone: 972-499-0647 Email: <a href="mailto:tim@creationix.com">tim@creationix.com</a>
Portfolio: <a href="mailto:www.creationix.com">www.creationix.com</a>

# Summary

I have worked many years in different fields, but out of all my work I've enjoyed the most (and been the best at) web programming. I have over 12 years total programming experience. I've done it for school, work, and fun and I know the little things that can cause problems and how to avoid them. I practice best-practices and insist on clean, easy-to-maintain code. My style of coding has been beneficial to many of the companies I've worked for in both maintenance and overall cost to develop. I adhere to strict standards compliance and constantly research the latest and greatest in programming techniques. I'm confident that my unique skills will be a great asset to any programming project.

# **Technical Skills**

### **Languages and Technologies**

- HTML/XHTML (7 years)
- > CSS (4 years)
- > AJAX (3 years)
- Ruby / Rails (1 year)
- | Javascript (8 years)
- > PHP (5 years)
- Linux (5 years)
- OSX (3 years)
- > Apache (5 years)

- MySQL (2 years)
- Postgresql (1 year)
- Python (3 years)
- GTK/Glade (2 years)
- Basic (12 years)
- > SSH (3 years)
- Java (1 year)
- > C (1 year)
- > C++ (1 year)

# **Education**

# **University of Texas at Dallas**

Major: Degrees:

**Estimated Completion:** 

Fall 2006 – Current Software Engineering

Bachelor's & Master's of Science

Spring 2010

Texarkana College

Major: Degree: Fall 2005-Summer 2006 Pre-Engineering N/A

**Southern Arkansas University** 

Major: Degree: Fall 2004 Pre-Engineering N/A

**University of Central Arkansas** 

Major: Degree:

Fall 2000-Spring 2001 Computer Science N/A

# **Professional Experience**

## New Media Gateway - Dallas, TX

2007 - Present

Web Developer

- Manage small team.
- > Designing, implementing, and debugging software

#### Miracom Network, Ltd. - Richardson, TX

2007

Programmer, System Admin

- > Work on a team to maintain a large web based application for remote print management.
- Administer and setup an integration server and several web servers.

# **Robert Half Technologies** - Dallas, TX

2006 - 2007

Consultant / Web Developer

- Made websites for clients in PHP, Mysql
- Short support calls to fix Unix and Linux systems

#### Creationix Software Innovations - Richardson, TX 2000 - Present

Freelance Designer / Programmer

- Worked on small contracts and designed in-house products
- > Web Design using PHP, Python, XHTML, CSS, Javascript, MySQL, Ruby, and Rails
- Custom board and card games
- > Open Source Development
- Linux systems administration
- Worked as main subcontractor to Phenom-Business-Solutions on several large sites.

### Texarkana Gazette - Texarkana, TX

2006

Online Production Technician

- Supervised the pre-press crew and assist as needed
- > Researched and developed new computer technologies for the company. (Using Linux and Open source programs)
- > Technical Support for close to 250 workstations.
- Maintained internal websites and servers

#### Insty-Prints - Texarkana, TX

2005 - 2006

Graphic Designer / Web Design Specialist

- Web design and maintenance for company and customers
- > Typesetting, graphic design, logo design and printing
- Customer Service, Research and Design, Marketing

#### **EPES** – Magnolia, AR

2004

Programmer / Designer

- > Designed and proposed in-house software
- Developed and programmed software in Java and Python
- > Tested software and trained employees on how to use software.

Tim Caswell Confidential 2